Finding aid to the Annetta Isabel Clark Papers CA.MS.00048
Smith College Archives
Annetta Isabel Clark Papers
1891-1961
Smith College Archives
Clark, Annetta Isabel, 1881-1961
CA.MS.00048
3.25 linear feet (5 containers)
Class of 1904, Secretary to the Smith College President (1909-46) and to the Smith College Board of Trustees (1919-1952). Collection contains biographical material, correspondence, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Annetta Isabel Clark was born in Northampton, MA on April 30, 1881 to Edwin Cook Clark and Mona C. Vogel Clark. Clark attended Northampton High School and graduated from Smith College with the class of 1904. From 1904-05 Clark taught at Springfield Business College, and between 1905-07 taught high school in Perth Amboy, NJ before returning to Smith as Assistant Registrar. From 1909-46, Clark worked as secretary to the President at Smith for the first four presidents of the college, as well as Secretary to the Board of Trustees from 1919-52 and Secretary to the Faculty from 1922-24.
Clark was active in many organizations, and served as secretary and president of the Northampton Community Chest, was a member of the Board of Directors of the Northampton Red Cross, and served as secretary of the Smith Student Aid Society. She was also a member of the Business and Professional Women's Association and served as the secretary of the Hampshire County branch of the American Association of University Women for two years. In 1929, the college awarded Clark an honorary MA degree. Clark retired from her work at Smith officially in 1952.
Clark died at the age of 80 on October 9, 1961 after a lingering illness.
Scope and Contents
The Annetta Isabel Clark Papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, numerous photographs, writings, and tributes spanning Clark's career as a staff member at Smith College.
Related Material
Class of 1904 Records
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Clark, Annetta Isabel, 1881-1961
- Biographical Materials, 1938; n. d. (Box 713, Folder 1)
- Birthdays, 1891; 1952 (Box 713, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Abbott, Jere, 1936-1960 (Box 713, Folder 3)
- Ainsworth, Dorothy S., 1960 (Box 713, Folder 4)
- Allen, Mary Adele, 1939 (Box 713, Folder 5)
- Blakeslee, Albert F., 1952 (Box 713, Folder 6)
- Bourland, Caroline Brown, 1939 (Box 713, Folder 7)
- Burton, Nina, 1934 (Box 713, Folder 8)
- Byard, Margaret (Mather), 1933 (Box 713, Folder 9)
- Caverno, Julia H., 1941 (Box 713, Folder 10)
- Clark, Annetta (to others), 1934-56 (Box 713, Folder 11)
- Coolidge, Grace G., 1935; 1946 (Box 713, Folder 12)
- Cutler, Anna Alice, 1941-42 (Box 713, Folder 13)
- Davis, Gladys W., n. d. (Box 713, Folder 14)
- Davis, Hallie F., 1942; 1952 (Box 713, Folder 15)
- Davis, Herbert, 1940-57 (Box 713, Folder 16)
- Deane, Sidney N., 1928; n. d. (Box 713, Folder 17)
- Folinsbee, John F., 1948 (Box 713, Folder 18)
- Galbraith, A. V., 1939 (Box 713, Folder 19)
- Garrison, Eleanor, 1949 (Box 713, Folder 20)
- Greene, Helen French, 1946 (Box 713, Folder 21)
- Grierson, Margaret Storrs, 1960 (Box 713, Folder 22)
- Halverson, Harlan, 1941 (Box 713, Folder 23)
- Hill, Justina H., 1942 (Box 713, Folder 24)
- Hodgkinson, Laura (Cabot), 1950 (Box 713, Folder 25)
- Huntington, Frances (Carpenter), undated (Box 713, Folder 26)
- Kane, Amanda (Bryan), 1927 (Box 713, Folder 27)
- Lamont, Thomas S., 1951 (Box 713, Folder 28)
- Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1935 (Box 713, Folder 29)
- McElwain, Mary Belle, 1952 (Box 713, Folder 30)
- Mensel, Mary Elizabeth, 1952 (Box 713, Folder 31)
- Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter, 1929-54 (Box 713, Folder 32)
- Morrow, Elisabeth Reeve, n. d (Box 713, Folder 33)
- Neilson, Allan, 1918 (Box 713, Folder 34)
- Neilson, Margaret, 1943 (Box 713, Folder 35)
- Neilson, William Allen, 1917; 1944 (Box 713, Folder 36)
- Nicolson, Marjorie H., n. d. (Box 713, Folder 37)
- Patch, Howard R., 1961 (Box 713, Folder 38)
- Perry, Alice (Cone), 1913 (Box 713, Folder 29)
- Randall, Helen W., 1946 (Box 713, Folder 40)
- Sabel, G. A., 1934 (Box 713, Folder 41)
- Seelye, L. Clark, 1907 (Box 713, Folder 42)
- Snow, Judith Johnston, 1957 (Box 713, Folder 43)
- Stevenson, George S., 1949 (Box 713, Folder 44)
- Thorp, Margaret Farrand, 1955 (Box 713, Folder 45)
- Turner, J. W. Cecil, 1942 (Box 713, Folder 46)
- Vorenkamp, Alphons, 1934-42 (Box 713, Folder 47)
- Withington, Robert, 1952; 1954 (Box 713, Folder 48)
- Wright, Benjamin Fletcher, 1949 (Box 713, Folder 49)
- Wright, Polly, undated (Box 713, Folder 50)
- Ainsworth family albums and photographs (Box 713.1)
- Crossword Puzzles, n. d. (Box 713, Folder 51)
- Diplomas, Certificates and Honorary Degree, 1929 (Box 713, Folder 52)
- Elizabeth Morrow School, 1956 (Box 713, Folder 53)
- Emeritus, 1952 (Box 713, Folder 54)
- Family Record, n. d. (Box 713, Folder 55)
- General, 1923-52 (Box 714, Folder 1)
- Handwriting Analysis, 1952 (Box 714, Folder 2)
- Holland Relief, 1953 (Box 714, Folder 3)
- Ink-blot Autographs, 1908-16 (Box 714, Folder 4)
- Hard Lines by Ogden Nash, 1931 (Box 714, Folder 5)
- Neilson of Smith College, Corrections, n. d. (Box 714, Folder 6)
- Neilson of Smith College, Publications, 1955 (Box 714, Folder 7)
- Notes, 1910-13 (Box 714, Folder 8)
- Obituaries, 1961 (Box 714, Folder 9)
- Oral history interview with Miles Henley, 1934 (Box 714, Folder 10)
- Pins and Seal, 1904 (Box 714, Folder 11)
- Presidents of Smith College, n. d. (Box 714, Folder 12)
- Publications, 1954 (Box 714, Folder 13)
- Scholarship, 1961 (Box 714, Folder 14)
- Sketches, n. d. (Box 714, Folder 15)
- Speeches, 1932-57 (Box 714, Folder 16)
- Tributes, 1952 (Box 714, Folder 17)
- Verse and Prose (Box 714, Folder 18)
- Photographs, 1904-1959 (Box 715, Folder 1)
- Photographs, n. d. (Box 715, Folder 2)
- Photo Album I, 1934-1951 (Box 715)
- Photo Album II, 1946-1951 (Box 715)
- Retirement, 1952 (Box 716, Folder 1)
- Retirement Party, 1952 (Box 716, Folder 2)
- Framed Photograph, n. d. (Box 716)
- Relief by Marion Wakeman, 1952 (Box 716)